Gabriel Luiz Vasconcellos

+5521972222345 | gabrielluiz.neves@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/glvasconcellos

Portifolio: gabrielvasconcellos.github.io

SUMMARY

I am a Software Engineer with over three years of experience seeking to transition from web development to game development. During my college years, I gained more than a year of hands-on experience as a game developer using Unity, culminating in the publication of a desktop game on Steam.

SKILLS

Languages: C#, Python, C++, Typescript, Javascript, CSS, SQL (Postgres)

Game Engines: Unity, Unreal Engine

Frameworks: React.js, Next.js, Jest, FastAPI, Pytest, Storybook

Developer Tools: Git, Docker, CI/CD, AWS

EXPERIENCE

Unity C# Game Developer

ago 2019 - jan 2021

ICAD Games/VisionLab

- Developed and released "Shape Arena" on <u>Steam</u>, implementing core gameplay systems, including procedural items and hazards spawning, knockback physics, player skills activation/cooldown, match system and menus;
- Developed a space defense game, "Chroma Eagle", in two days for a game jam. Implemented airship movement based on aircraft principal axes, mechanics for defense, repair, and resource management, requiring players to gather materials from enemies to repair stations;
- Developed "Tamapote," a pet care game. Implemented pet aging, management system to track pet needs based on time spent with the game open and closed, an in-game store, UI menus and save system;

Mid-level Software Engineer

October 2023 – Present

OLX Group

- Developed a system for user journey personalization based on purchased features (Python, FastAPI, Typescript and React.js)
- Implemented an automatic login feature when redirecting from partner website via account binding using oAuth 2.0 for authorization (Python, FastAPI, Typescript and React.js)
- Developed a landing page with lead notification and a user registration system for marketing campaigns (Python, FastAPI, Typescript, React.js and Next.js)
- Contributed to the Design System by creating and extending components used across all web applications within the company (React.js and Typescript)

Junior Software Engineer

December 2021 – October 2023

OLX Group

- Developed a price comparison meter to inform buyers and sellers how an ad's price is compared to all OLX platform (React.js and Typescript)
- Created a new photo and video gallery component for ad pages (React.js and Typescript)
- Redesigned the ads listing to include grid view and visual improvements (React.js and Typescript)

Software Development Intern

July 2021 – December 2021

 $OLX \ Group$

• Developed a new homepage for the automobile section of the OLX marketplace (Next.js, React, and TypeScript)

EDUCATION

Pontifical Catholic University of Rio de Janeiro - PUC-Rio

Rio de Janeiro, RJ - Brasil

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

March 2018 - December 2022

LANGUAGES

English: Full professional Portuguese: Native